Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Joseph Lindon Smith papers
1647-1965, bulk 1873-1965
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Smith, Joseph Lindon
8.8 linear feet
The papers of Boston and New Hampshire painter Joseph Lindon Smith date from 1647-1965, with the bulk of papers dating from 1873-1965, and measure 8.8 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical materials; letters from family members, artists, museums, and art patrons; seven diaries by Smith and two by his wife Corinna, personal business records, notes and writings, files concerning charitable theatrical productions, one sketchbook and other art work, a scrapbook, printed material, photographs, and sound recordings of radio interviews and a radio program on Smith.
Provenance
The Joseph Lindon Smith papers were donated by Jessie T. Hale, Smith's granddaughter, in 1977 and 1978.
Related Material
The papers of Smith's wife, Corinna Putnam Smith, are available at The Schlesinger Library of Radcliffe College, Cambridge, Massachusetts.
Alternative Forms Available
The collection is available on 35 mm microfilm reels 5114-5124 at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the collection as described in this finding aid may not reflect the exact order of the collection on microfilm. All of the sound recordings in this collection were digitized for research access in 2009 and are available at the Archives of American Art offices. Researchers may view the original phonograph records for the archival notations on them, but original media are not available for playback.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Joseph Lindon Smith (1863-1950) of Boston, Massachusetts and Dublin, New Hampshire, was a painter primarily known for his ability to meticulously depict the murals and tomb sculpture of Egypt and other ancient cultures.
Joseph Lindon Smith was born on October 11, 1863 in Pawtucket, Rhode Island, the son of wholesale lumberman Henry Francis Smith and Emma Greenleaf Smith, a cousin of John Greenleaf Whittier.
From 1880 to 1882, Smith studied drawing and painting at the Art School of the Boston Museum of Fine Arts under Frederic Crowninshield and Otto Grundman. Accompanied by his friend, Frank Benson, he attended the Académie Julian and studied under William Bouguereau, Gustave Boulanger, and Jules Lefebvre from 1883 to 1885.
Upon his return to Boston, Smith established a studio as a portrait and landscape painter, attracting the attention of Denman Ross, a professor of History of Fine Arts at Harvard University. In the early 1890s Smith and Ross began to travel extensively and Smith became interested in ancient civilizations of Mexico, China, and Southeast Asia. In 1892, during a trip to Italy, Smith befriended Isabella Stewart Gardner, for whom he copied famous paintings, and occasionally acted as agent in purchasing art work.
Making his first trip to Egypt in 1898, Smith became enthralled with the art work of the ancient civilization and devoted himself to painting copies of the tomb sculptures and murals for educational uses in museums and other public institutions. In 1899, he married Corinna Haven Putnam and the couple spent much of their married life traveling between the United States and the Middle East, especially Egypt. From 1910 to 1939, Smith was a member of the Joint Expedition of the Boston Museum of Fine Arts and Harvard University directed by Dr. George A. Reisner.
For fifty years, Smith was also sought out as a writer and producer of plays and theatrical pageants, fetes, and masques primarily staged for various charitable fund-raising events.
Joseph Lindon Smith died on October 18, 1950 in Dublin, New Hampshire.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Boston and New Hampshire painter Joseph Lindon Smith date from 1647-1965, with the bulk of papers dating from 1873-1965, and measure 8.8 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical materials; letters from family members, artists, museums, and art patrons; seven diaries by Smith and two by his wife Corinna, personal business records, notes and writings, files concerning charitable theatrical productions, one sketchbook and other art work, a scrapbook, printed material, photographs, and sound recordings of radio interviews and a radio program on Smith.
Scattered biographical material consists of family history documents for the Smith and Putnam families, a Jenkes family tree, and passports for Joseph Lindon Smith and his family.
Over three linear feet of letters are from family members, artists including Cecilia Beaux, Frank Benson, George DeForest Brush, and Denman Ross, museum staff concerned with work in Egypt, and art patrons including Isabella Stewart Gardner, and individuals involved with Smith's charitable pageants. There are scattered letters from Lawrence Alma-Tadema, Henry James, Charles G. Loring, Paul Manship, General John J. Pershing, John Singer Sargent, and Abbott Handerson Thayer. Among the subjects discussed are student life at the Académie Julian, the Smiths' travels, and individuals known by Smith.
Seven diaries written by Joseph Lindon Smith document his ravels in Egypt, Persia, Europe, and New Mexico. Two diaries were written by Corinna Smith during her travels to Beiram and Egypt.
Personal business records business records include contracts, price lists, lists of securities, and miscellaneous receipts of the Smith and Putnam families, Joseph Lindon Smith, Corinna Smith, and their daughter Lois Smith.
Notes include engagement calendars, notebooks, lists of art work, lecture notes, minutes of meetings, notes on family history and on travel, and an autograph by Kit Carson. Writings include miscellaneous typescripts by the Smiths and others concerning travel, work in Egypt and elsewhere, and anecdotes about various friends and acquaintances. There are also three drafts of "Egypt - My Winter Home."
Theatrical production files concern plays, pageants, and masques written and/or produced by the Smiths. Many of the performances were benefits, dedication or anniversary celebrations, such as a pageant given at Fenway Court in honor of Isabella Stewart Gardner, a pageant at the dedication of a memorial to Abbott Handerson Thayer, and the centenary celebration of the founding of Amherst, Massachusetts.
Art work includes a sketchbook with extensive notes, a painting, drawings by Joseph Lindon Smith, and prints by other artists.
A scrapbook contains clippings and an exhibition catalog from the St. Botolph Club. Additional printed material includes clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, press releases, programs, booklets, brochures, and books by others.
Photographs are of Smith, his family, friends including classmates from the Académie Julian, Isabella Stewart Gardner, Abbott Handerson Thayer, exhibition installations, military camp sites from World War I, travel scenes, and art work by Smith.
Audio recordings consist of four sound disc recordings of interviews for WKNE Radio, Keene, New Hampshire, with Corinna Smith and Barry Faulkner talking about Smith, and a program about Smith and his book Tombs, Temples, and Ancient Art.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 11 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1711-1948 (Box 1, 10; 5 folders)
Series 2: Letters, 1768-1965 (Box 1-4, OV 11; 3.5 linear feet)
Series 3: Diaries, 1904-1949 (Box 4; 11 folders)
Series 4: Personal Business Records, 1647-1959 (Box 4, 10; 11 folders)
Series 5: Notes and Writings, 1783-1963 (Box 4-6; 2.0 linear feet)
Series 6: Theatrical Production Files, 1897-1950 (Box 6-7, 10; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 7: Art Works, 1932-1943 (Box 8, 10; 8 folders)
Series 8: Scrapbook, 1888-1901 (Box 8; 1 folder)
Series 9: Printed Material, 1723-1963 (Box 8, OV 11; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 10: Photographs, 1884-1956 (Box 8-10; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 11: Audio Recordings, 1956 (Box 9-10; 2 folders)
All material is arranged chronologically except for the writings by others and travel photographs that are arranged alphabetically.
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Gardner, Isabella Stewart, 1840-1924; Thayer, Abbott Handerson, 1849-1921; Académie Julian
Subjects-Topical:
Art, Egypt; Art, Egyptian; Art, Ancient; Historical drama; Community theater; Painters, New Hampshire, Dublin
Subjects-Geographical:
Egypt, Antiquities; Egypt, Description and travel
Types of Materials:
Drafts (documents); Drawings; Diaries; Interviews; Notebooks; Photographs; Prints; Scrapbooks; Sketchbooks; Sound recordings
Names:
Alma-Tadema, Lawrence, Sir, 1836-1912; Beaux, Cecilia, 1855-1942; Benson, Frank Weston, 1862-1951; Brush, George de Forest, 1855-1941; Carson, Kit, 1809-1868; James, Henry, 1843-1916; Loring, Charles Greely, 1828-1902; Manship, Paul, 1885-1966; Pershing, John J. (John Joseph, 1860-1948; Ross, Denman Waldo, 1853-1935; Sargent, John Singer, 1856-1925; Smith, Corinna Lindon, 1876-; Thayer, Abbott Handerson, 1849-1921
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1711-1948, Series 1:; (Box 1, 10; 5 folders)
  Biographical material consists of documents for both the Smith and Putnam family and for Joseph Lindon Smith and Corinna Putnam Smith, including certificates of birth, marriage, and military commissions, a Jenkes family tree, and passports for the Smiths.
  - Documents for Smith and Putnam Ancestors, 1711-1864, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Documents for Joseph Lindon Smith and Family, 1900-1948, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 10) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Passports, 1900-1918, undated, (from Box 1, Folder 5) (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Letters, 1768-1965, Series 2:; (Box 1-4, OV 11; 3.5 linear feet)
  Letters are primarily from family members, artists, museum staff concerned with work in Egypt, and art patrons involved with Smith's charitable pageants. Correspondents include Cecilia Beaux, Frank Benson, George DeForest Brush, Isabella Stewart Gardner, and Denman Ross. There are scattered letters from Lawrence Alma-Tadema, Henry James, Charles G. Loring, Paul Manship, General John J. Pershing, John Singer Sargent, and Abbott Handerson Thayer.
  See Index of Correspondents for Series 2.
  Index of Correspondents for Series 2
  Abbas, Abdul Baba, 1912
  Abbott, Holker, 1917
  Abdullah, Mohamed, 1938
  Abingdon, The Countess of, 1940, 1941
  Aldrich, Eleanor, 1940
  Aldrich, J.B., 1896
  Aldrich, William T., 1931
  Alexander, L.G., 1894
  Alma Tadema, Sir Lawrence, 1894
  American Express Company, 1934
  American Federation of Arts, 1940, 1941, 1942
  American Red Cross, 1917, 1945, 1946
  Baldwin, Florence, 1898
  Baltimore Museum of Art, 1941, 1943
  Bartlett, Frederic Clay, 1910
  Bass, R.P. and Edith, 1932, 1932
  Beaulieu, Elizabeth, 1943
  Beaux, Cecilia, undated, 1899
  Bennett, Esther, 1895, 1899
  Bennett, Sophie, 1897, 1899, 1903
  Benson, Eugene, undated
  Benson, Frank Weston, 1899, 1943, 1945
  Berenson, Bernard, 1897
  Bey, Sahfik Ghorbal, 1948, 1949
  Bey, A. Heikal, 1948, 1949
  Bigelow, W. Sturgis, undated, 1893, 1901
  Bittinger, Charles, 1950
  Bliss, Robert Woods and Mildred, 1916, 1940
  Boston Breeze, 1931
  Bradley, Kate A., 1919
  Breasted, Charles, 1931
  Breckingham, Eugenia B., 1893, 1943
  Brejant, Grace M., 1895
  Brewster, Frederick and Margaret, 1936
  Bridges, Styles, 1939, 1940
  British War Relief Society, 1941
  Brooklyn Museum, 1933, 1943
  Brown family, undated, 1894, 1895, 1986, 1899
  Brown, Frederick and Ida, 1894, 1895, 1896, 1897, 1900
  Brown University, 1929
  Brummer Gallery, Inc., 1937
  Brush, George de Forest, 1894, 1895, 1896, 1897, 1898, 1935
  Buck, Matilda S., 1897
  Buffalo Fine Arts Academy, 1912, 1917
  Burbank, Mr., 1943
  Cabot, Arthur J. and Sally, 1896
  Calhoun, Lucy, 1910
  Cambridge: Superintendent of Schools, 1942, 1943
  Carey, Arthur Astor, 1902
  Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1931
  Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1940, 1941, 1942
  Carter, Mary Duncan, 1937
  Cartland, Joseph, 1898
  Chace, Lucretia G., 1909
  Chandler, J.E., 1894
  Chicago: Art Institute of Chicago, 1911
  Chinese Republic, 1944
  Churchill, Winston, 1901, 1945
  Clements, Cyril, 1946
  Coca Cola Company, 1943
  Constable, William George and Olivia, undated, 1942, 1943, 1949
  Coolidge, Anne, 1940
  Coolidge, John Templeman, 1894
  Coolidge, Katie S., undated, 1899, 1900
  Coolidge, Katrine (Cara), undated, 1898, 1899, 1900
  Coolidge, Molly, undated, 1893
  Cravath, Paul D., 1922, 1930, 1931
  Crawford, Cheryl, 1930
  Crowninshield, Frederic, 1882
  Curtis, Daniel Sargent, 1897
  Cushing, Tom, 1913
  Cutting, W. Bayard and Sybil, 1909
  Dallas, John T., 1929, 1931, 1940, 1942
  Dartmouth College, 1929
  Dawes, Charles G., 1930
  Day, Frank Miles, 1897, 1898
  de Beaumont, Renee, 1897, 1898
  de Bildt, Harold, 1938, 1939
  de Forest, Mrs., 1940
  dell'Albergo Leon Bianco, Raffaella, 1906
  de Marco, Marchese e Marchesa De Viti, undated
  de Monbrison, H., 1923
  Dewey, Thomas E., 1941
  Doe: Miss Jessie Doe Children's Aid Society, 1941
  Dublin School, 1947
  DuBois, Francis and Betty, 1943, 1944
  Eddy, Augustin, 1910
  Egyptian Education Bureau, 1947
  Eliot, Grace H., 1889
  Ellis, Ray and Alice, 1946
  Ely, Gertrude, 1916
  Emery, Prof. W.B., 1957
  Evan, Evans, 1917
  Fairbanks, Arthur, 1922
  Fairchild family, undated, 1894
  Fairchild, Sally, undated, 1891
  Farraud, Beatrix, 1924
  Fernald, Reginald, 1914
  Fields, Annie, 1900
  Fitzgerald, Fred and Abbie, 1947, 1949, 1950
  Fitzhugh, Armistead, 1946
  Folkways, 1948
  Foreign Relations, Senate Committee on, 1909
  Fuertes, Katharine, 1942
  Fuller, Robert, 1898
  Galleria Simonetti, 1902
  Garden Club of Dublin, 1943
  Gardner, Isabella Stewart, 1894, 1899, 1900, 1903, 1904, 1905, 1906, 1907, 1919, 1921
  Gardner, Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, 1945, 1955
  Gardner, John L., 1898
  Gardner, Agnes, 1894
  Garrison, Frank J., 1889
  Gay, Mrs. Walter, 1920
  General Theological Seminary Library, 1939
  Graziani, Adolfo, 1903
  Greek War Relief Association, 1944
  Greene, Henry Copley, 1893, 1897
  Greene, Lois Anna, undated, 1883, 1884, 1886, 1887, 1892, 1895, 1896, 1897, 1898, 1899, 1901, 1902, 1910, 1914, 1915, 1916, 1917, 1918, 1919, 1921, 1922
  Greene, Mary Amory, undated, 1893
  Greenough, Charles P., 1898
  Gugler, Eric, 1948
  Hallowell, (Aunt) Sally, 1897, 1900, 1902
  Hamamsi, Ali Bey, 1949
  Hamed, H., 1909
  Harkness, Edward, 1931
  Harrigan, D. Ward, 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944
  Harrison, DeSales, 1943
  Harrowby, Lady, 1927
  Hart, Francis R., 1929
  Harvard University (Peabody Museum), 1931, 1933, 1934, 1936, 1939, 1940, 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944, 1946, 1947, 1948, 1952
  Hauff, L.B., 1940
  Hearst, Phoebe A., 1899
  Hemenway, Augustus and Harriet, 1931
  Henderson, Mrs. William P., 1928
  Heneidy, Abdel-Lateef Erfan, 1948
  Higgins, John W., 1940
  Higginson, Col. Henry L., 1898, 1905, 1931
  Higginson, Thomas Wentworth and Ida, 1893, 1896
  Hill, Aunt Nellie, 1921
  Hillard, Mary R., 1932
  Hodge, Zarah, 1932
  Hopkinson, Charles, 1899
  Houghton, Mifflin Company, 1930
  Howells, Mildred, undated
  Howells, W.D., 1891
  Hughes, Dudley and Francis Smith, 1942, 1943, 1944, 1945
  Hussein, Abd Essalam, 1948
  Jaccaci, 1930
  James, Mrs. Alexander, undated, 1946, 1948, 1963
  James, Arthur Curtiss and Harriet, undated, 1914, 1920, 1924, 1929, 1937, 1938, 1939, 1940
  James, Henry, undated
  James, William, 1943
  Jenks [Jencks], John, 1768, 1782
  Jones, Robert Edmond, 1946
  Kaneko, Kentaro, 1901, 1904
  Kelekian, F., 1929, 1931, 1932
  Kendall Hall School, 1944
  Kenyon College, 1923
  Keppell, Frederick P., 1931, 1940
  Komai, S., 1901
  Landwehr, Juan, undated
  Lang, A. Hamilton, 1900
  Lauzirotti, A., 1892, 1896
  Lawrence, Elizabeth, 1896, 1897
  Loeser, Charles, undated
  Loevenich, Karl, 1946, 1947, 1948
  Lombard, Mrs. Percival H., undated
  Loring, Charles Greely, 1900
  Lothrop, Thornton, 1894
  Lowell, Carlotta Russell, 1892
  MacDowell, M., 1910, 1915, 1943
  MacVeagh, Emil, undated, 1950
  MacVeagh, Fannie, 1940
  MacVeagh, Franklin, 1899, 1928, 1931
  Malicheff, Michael G. (Nick) and Rebecca Smith, 1939, 1940, 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944, 1945, 1946
  Manship, Paul, 1942, 1943, 1948
  Massachusetts Bay Colony Tercentenary Commission, 1929, 1930
  Mauran, Isabel, undated, 1945, 1947, 1948, 1950
  McKittrick, Margaret, undated
  McLean, Gardiner, 1908
  Meriden Bird Club, Inc., 1949, 1950
  Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1941, 1946
  Metropolitan Opera Company, 1924
  Meyer, Mr., 1903
  Middle East Institute, 1948
  Missouri, University of, 1940
  Mitchell, S. Weir, 1899, 1900
  Mohammed, Dowe, 1902, 1903
  Mongiardini, Gemma, 1903
  Moore, Charles H., 1894, 1903
  Morley, Sylvanus, 1939, 1940, 1941
  Mountbatten, Lady Louis (Edwina), 1940
  Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1900, 1905, 1906, 1909, 1910, 1915, 1922, 1924, 1925, 1928, 1929, 1930, 1931, 1934, 1935, 1936, 1937, 1938, 1939, 1940, 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944, 1945, 1946, 1947, 1952
  Museum School Alumni Association, 1931
  Nelson Gallery of Art/Atkins Museum of Fine Arts, 1949, 1950
  New Hampshire Children's Aid and Protective Society, 1940, 1941
  New Hampshire Committee to Help Hampshire, England, 1940, 1941, 1942
  New Hampshire, University of, 1948, 1949, 1950
  New Hampshire War Chest, Inc., 1943, 1946
  New York Public Library, 1936, 1949
  New York Times, 1928
  Norton, C.E., 1894, 1901
  Okakura, K., 1901
  Offner, Richard, 1929, 1930
  Oriental Institute, University of Chicago, 1931, 1934, 1935, 1938
  Osgood, Hamilton, 1900
  Otaki, H.K., 1901
  Otis, Joseph E., 1928, 1938, 1942
  Otis, Raymond and Frances Smith, 1928, 1929, 1930, 1931, 1932, 1933, 1934, 1935, 1936, 1937, 1938, 1939
  Paderewski, Ignace Jan, 1941
  Page, Henrietta, 1899
  Parker, A. Stanley, 1923
  Parker, Herbert, 1929
  Parrish, Isabel M., 1898
  Parrish, Maxfield, 1943
  Pasha, Nokrashi, 1948
  Pasha, Sanhoury, 1947, 1948, 1949
  Patterson, Jefferson, 1937
  Peabody Museum, Salem, 1913
  Pell, Madeline, undated, 1930
  Pennsylvania, University of, 1931, 1940
  Pershing, Gen. John J., 1940
  Persian Legation, 1934
  Peters, John P., 1899
  Petrie, Graham, undated
  Petrie, W.M., undated
  Platt, H., 1897
  Platt, Charles Adams, 1893
  Pollard, John, 1935
  Pope, 1932
  Porter, Mrs. James F., 1911
  Pratt family, 1901, 1916, 1942, 1943, 1945
  Providence Art Club, 1912
  Pumpelly, Raphael and Eliza, 1913, 1914, 1915, 1919
  Putnam, Bertha, 1940
  Putnam, Corinna, 1899
  Putnam, Ethel F., 1921, 1940
  Putnam, George Palmer, 1924, 1932
  Putnam, (G.P. Putnam's sons), 1938
  Putnam, George Haven and Fannie, 1894, 1899, 1900
  Putnam, V., 1897
  Quibell, Edward, 1915, 1930, 1932
  Ramadan, A.M., 1950
  Ray, Margaret L., 1913
  Reasoner family, 1943
  Regali, Domenico, 1903
  Reisner, George A., 1908, 1929, 1931, 1933, 1935, 1936, 1937, 1938, 1939
  Richards, Beverley, 1919
  Ringling, Mr., undated
  Robertson, I., 1903
  Robinson, Edward (Ned), 1891, 1894, 1895, 1896, 1897, 1899
  Rochat, Giovanni, undated
  Rockefeller, Nelson, 1943
  Rodman Gallery, 1935
  Rollins College, 1945
  Roosevelt, George, 1943
  Roosevelt, Nicholas, 1950
  Ross, Denman, 1888, 1892, 1893, 1899, 1900, 1901, 1904, 1905, 1913, 1916, 1917, 1919, 1920, 1922, 1928, 1929, 1931, 1934, 1935
  Ross, Frances W., 1891, 1892, 1893, 1895, 1901
  Rossi-Scotti, Roberio, 1907
  Russell, Theodore, 1909
  Saarinen, Aline, undated
  St. Louis Pageant and Masque, 1914
  Saint Louis Pageant Drama Association, 1917
  Salamah, Dowi M., undated
  Sargent, John Singer, undated, 1900, 1909
  Sargent, Nellie, 1899
  Sargent, Violet, 1890
  Saunders, Frederick W., undated
  Schieffelin, John Jay and Lois, 1932, 1933, 1934, 1935, 1936, 1937, 1938, 1939, 1940, 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944, 1945
  Schieffelin, Johnnie, 1943
  Schoen, Gretchen, 1921
  School, Art League of New York City, 1931
  School of Decorative Design, 1931
  Schuyler, Philip, 1899
  Schweinfurth, J.A., 1931
  Sears, Sarah, 1897, 1898, 1904
  Sears, Taber, undated
  Sebasti and Reali, 1903
  Senate Committee on Foreign Relations, 1909
  Servien, Jose, undated
  Seymour, S.O., 1913
  Shaw, Pauline, undated, 1895
  Shaw, Quincy, 1896, 1897, 1901
  Shaw, S.P., undated
  Shohday, Abbas Helmy, 1948
  Simkhovitch, Vladimir G., 1944
  Simmons College, 1942
  Simmons, Mrs. Franklin, 1903
  Simmons, George and Virginia, 1914, 1922
  Sims, William S., 1932
  Skinner, Alice Parrish, 1940
  Smith, Corinna Putnam, 1910, 1911, 1912, 1913, 1914, 1915, 1916, 1917, 1918, 1919, 1920, 1921, 1922, 1923, 1924, 1925, 1926, 1927, 1928, 1929, 1930, 1931, 1932, 1933, 1934, 1935, 1936, 1937, 1938, 1939, 1940, 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944
  Smith, Florence A., 1908
  Smith, Frances, undated, 1908, 1913, 1915, 1916, 1917, 1918, 1919, 1920, 1921, 1922, 1923, 1925
  Smith, Henry Francis and Emma Greenleaf Smith, 1848, 1878, 1899, 1900, 1901, 1902, 1903, 1904, 1905, 1906, 1907, 1908, 1909
  Smith, Joseph Lindon, 1882, 1883, 1884, 1885, 1886, 1887, 1888, 1889, 1890, 1891, 1892, 1893, 1894, 1895, 1896, 1897, 1898, 1899, 1900, 1901, 1902, 1903, 1904, 1905, 1906, 1907, 1908, 1909, 1910, 1911, 1912, 1913, 1914, 1915, 1916, 1917, 1918, 1919, 1920, 1921, 1922, 1923, 1924, 1925, 1926, 1927, 1928, 1929, 1930, 1931, 1932, 1933, 1934, 1935, 1936, 1937, 1938, 1939, 1940, 1941, 1942, 1943, 1944, 1945, 1946
  Smith, Lois Lindon, undated, 1914, 1918, 1919, 1920, 1921, 1922, 1923, 1924, 1926, 1927, 1928, 1929, 1930, 1932
  Smith, M. Linton, 1900
  Smith, Rebecca, 1908, 1918, 1919, 1920, 1922
  Smith-Petersen, M.N., 1932, 1946
  Smithsonian Institution, 1949, 1950
  Society of Arts and Crafts, Boston, 1901
  Spaulding, Huntley N., 1940, 1942
  State, Department of, 1908, 1934, 1940, 1947
  Stearns, Foster, 1941
  Stebbins, Roderick, 1912
  Steele, Asa, undated
  Steffins, Rev. Fr., undated
  Stevens, Thomas Wood, 1917, 1918
  Stevens, Thomas Wood Stevens Theatre Collection, 1942
  Stewart, E. Channing, 1900
  Stewart, George, 1943, 1945, 1947
  Stowell, Chan, 1914
  Strong, Margaret, 1916
  Stroud, Mary, 1903
  Sullivan, T. Russell and Lucy, 1895, 1897, 1899, 1901, 1906, 1909, 1913, 1916
  Tarbell, Ida M., 1930
  Tavern Club, 1911, 1917
  Taylor, Jessie, 1936, 1937, 1938, 1939, 1940, 1941, 1942, 1943
  Taylor, William and Rebecca Smith, 1932, 1933, 1935, 1936, 1937, 1938
  Teachman, Jessie, 1897, 1905
  Thayer, Abbott Handerson, undated
  Thayer, Abbott Handerson Thayer Memorial, 1941
  Tobey, Charles W., 1939, 1942
  Tomita, Kojiro, 1936, 1937, 1943, 1947
  Turner, C.Y., 1902
  Turner, Ross, 1896
  Union League Club, 1918
  United China Relief, Inc., 1944
  United Nations Relief Fund, 1942
  University Museum, University of Pennsylvania, 1931, 1943
  Vanderbilt, Mrs. George and Cornelia, 1923
  Vanelli, Caesar, 1929, 1930
  Vaughan, Henry Goodwin, 1936
  Volpi, Elia, 1903, 1904, 1905, 1907
  von Pustau, Helene, 1895, 1899
  Walters, Thorstina Jackson, 1929
  Wang, Lucy C., 1944
  War Finance Committee (New Hampshire), 1944
  Warren, H. Langford, 1907
  Warren, Harold B., 1931
  Webster, Laurence and Edith, 1941
  Webster, Sue, 1916
  Weems, Katharine Lane, 1965
  Wendelstadt, Baron Wendelstadt, 1894, 1896, 1897
  Wheeler, Roy R., 1932, 1946
  White, Elise, 1931
  Whitman, Paul, undated, 1893, 1899, 1901, 1902
  Willard, Belle, 1931
  Williams, Ben Ames, 1928
  Yale University, 1915, 1934
  Yamanaka and Company, 1930, 1931
  Young, Hugh H., 1941, 1942
  Zatelli, H., 1897
  - Letters from Correspondents with Unknown Surnames, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters from Correspondents with Surnames "A" - "B," undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Correspondents with Surnames "C," undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Correspondents with Surnames "D" - "F," undated (Box 1, Folder 9)